Another thing is when you are dribbling...and you have to dribble, you can't catch the ball and just start walking with it unless shooting or passing.
You have to dribble and move.
So your choices are to dribble and then pass.
Or you can take a dribble and shoot.
Now let's just say that you catch the ball from someone, and you're close in proximity to the basket, you get two steps after your dribble to shoot the ball.
So I catch the ball on the run, I'm jogging down, and I catch the ball on the run, from the time I grab the ball I get one step, two steps, and then I have to shoot it as a layup.
So you get two steps after you catch the ball.
And you can catch it on the fly, which means just catch it in the air, one, two, shot.
Or you can catch it and dribble, and when you dribble, once you pick up your dribble -- see because I'm moving my foot -- that's one step, two steps, shot.
So those are the basics of dribbling.